crably.com 2018-12-27

# Crably

### What This Privacy Policy Covers

This policy covers how Crably IVS ("Crably," "we," "us," or "our") treats personal information that it collects and receives on http://crably.com. We are not in the business of selling information about you: we use information shared with us for the sole purpose of running and improving our services. This notice tells you what information we collect, steps we take to protect and secure it, how we use and share information, and finally, how you can contact us with questions or concerns. 

This policy applies where we are acting as a Data Controller with respect to the Personal Data of our website visitors and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that Personal Data to be compliant with the GDPR. 

**Data** **Controller** ” means the natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the Processing of Personal Data. 

**GDPR** ” means the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data.

**Personal Data** ” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual where such information is contained within Customer Data and is protected similarly as personal data or personally identifiable information under applicable Data Protection Law

**Data Protection Law** ” means all applicable legislation relating to data protection and privacy including without limitation the EU Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC and all local laws and regulations which amend or replace any of them, including the GDPR, together with any national implementing laws in any Member State of the European Union or, to the extent applicable, in any other country, as amended, repealed, consolidated or replaced from time to time. The terms “process”, “processes” and “processed” will be construed accordingly.

Crably processes personal information and we have therefore adopted this privacy policy under the General Data Pretection Regulation (GDPR), which is the new European Personal Organization, which aims to protect you and your personal information.

We are, of course, living up to all the requirements for the protection of your personal information according to the GDPR. 

As we process personal information, we have adopted this Privacy Policy, which tells you how we treat your data.

If you can’t be identified (for example, when personal data has been aggregated and anonymised) then this notice doesn’t apply.

### Who are ‘we’? 

When we refer to “we” (or "Crably, "us," or "our"), that means Crably and all its wholly owned subsidiaries. Our company is located in Denmark. Address details for all Crably offices are available on our _Contact us_ page.

We provide an easy-to-use global online platform for any businesses and their private people.At the core of our platform is our cloud Software as a Service software. If you want to find out more about what we do, see the  _About Crably page_.

For European Union data protection purposes, when we act as a controller in relation to your personal data, Crably IVS (company number _DK_ 36043865) is our representative in the European Union.

### How we collect your data 

By visiting our websites or use our services, we collect personal data. The ways we collect it can be categorizedinto the following:

**Information you provide to us directly:** When you visit or use some parts of our websites and/or services we might ask you to provide personal data to us. For example, we ask for your contact and billing information when you sign up for our services, when you sign up for a free trial, respond to a job application or an email marketing, participate in community forums, join us on social media, take part in training and events, contact us with questions or request support. You have the option of course to not provide with personal data, and in this case you can’t use some parts of our websites or services.

**Information we collect automatically:** We sometimes collect some information about you automatically when you visit our websites or use our services, like your IP address for example. Sometimes wealso collect information when you navigate through our websites and services, including what pages you looked at and what links you clicked on. This information is useful for us as it helps us get a better understanding of how you’re using our websites and services in order to provide the best user experience possible. 

Part of this information is collected using cookies and similar tracking technologies. You can find out more about how we use of cookies, types, why, and how you can control them by reading our _cookie notice_.

**Information we receive from third parties:** The biggest part of information we collect, we collect directly from you. From time to time we might collect personal data about you from other sources, such as publicly available materials or trusted third parties like our marketing and research partners. We use this information to add extra quality to the personal data we already have about you, in order to better inform, personalizeand improve our services, and to validate the personal data you provide.

We will only use the collected personal data for the follow bellow:

  * To perform a contract with you, or

  * Where we have legitimate interests to process the personal data and they’re not overridden by your rights, or

  * In accordance with a legal obligation, or 

  * Where we have your consent.

In case we don’t collect your personal data, we may be unable to provide you with all our services, and some functions and features on our websites may not be available to you.   

In case you are a person who doesn’t have a connection/relation with us, but believe that a Crably subscriber has entered your personal data into our websites or services, you’ll need to contact that Crably subscriber for any questions you have about your personal data (including where you want to access, correct, amend, or request that the user delete, your personal data).

### Information We Gather

Crably collects personal information when you register with us, use Crably products or services or post content on a Crably website or blog. This information is limited to your email address, username, and any information you post on your site. Your password is stored securely. 

Crably may also collect personal information (user first name, user last name, user email, user phone, billing first name, billing last name, billing company, billing address line 1, billing city, billing zip, billing country, billing state, billing VAT number, website link, card first name, card last name, card number, card expiry card month, card expiry year, card CVV) if you enter into promotions. The personal data collected is the minimum necessary to create invoices. You can at anytime login into your control panel to edit your information and change/delete your credit card details as well. 

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. IP addresses, browser and session information may be used to: 

  * __Diagnose and prevent service or technology problems reported by our users or engineers that are associated with the IP addresses controlled by a specific web company or ISP.
  * __Estimate the total number of users visiting Crably's web sites from specific geographical regions.
  * __Help determine which users have access privileges to certain content, services or resources that we offer.
  * __Monitor and prevent fraud and abuse.

If you sign up for a paid service the billing information, which may include your name, address, telephone number, credit card details, and other information that is necessary in order to process the transaction will be collected and processed by a third party Payment Gateway (like Paypal, Stripe, Paymill, etc ). Under no circumstance do we store any of your sensitive billing details. 

Crably uses information for the following general purposes: products and services provision, identification and authentication, services improvement, support, contact, research, and anonymous reporting. 

### How we use your data

We use your personal data to operate our websites and provide you with any services you’ve requested, and to manage our relationship with you. We also use your personal data for other purposes, which may include the following:

**To support you:** providing resolution of technical support issues or other issues relating to the websites or services, whether by email, in-app support or otherwise.

**To communicate with you:**

  * Providing you with information you’ve requested from us (like questions) or information we are required to send to you

  * Operational communications, like changes to our websites and services, security updates, or assistance with using our websites and services

  * Marketing communications (about Crably or another product or service we think you might be interested in)

  * Asking you for feedback or to take part in any research we are conducting (which we may engage a third party to assist with).

**To enhance our websites and services and develop new ones:** For example, by tracking and monitoring your use of websites and services so we can keep improving, or by carrying out technical analysis of our websites and services so that we can optimizeyour user experience and provide you with more efficient tools.

**To protect:** So that we can detect and prevent any fraudulent or malicious activity, and make sure that everyone is using our websites and services fairly and in accordance with our _Terms of Use_.

**To market to you:**  In addition to sending you marketing communications, we may also use your personal data to display targeted advertising to you online – through our own websites and services or through third party websites and their platforms. **To analyse, aggregate and report:** We may use the personal data we collect about you and other users of our websites and services (whether obtained directly or from third parties) to produce aggregated and anonymised analytics and reports, which we may share publicly or with third parties.

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacy@crably.com.

### How we can share your data

Sometimes we need to share your personal data with third parties. Crably may share personal information about your personal data under the following circumstances:

  * Other companies in the Crably holding of companies

  * Third party service providers and partners who assist and enable us to use the personal data to, for example, support delivery of or provide functionality on the website or services, or to market or promote our goods and services to you

  * Regulators, law enforcement bodies, government agencies, courts or other third parties where we think it’s necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations, or to exercise, establish or defend our legal rights. Where possible and appropriate, we will notify you of this type of disclosure

  * We may share your personal information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our various terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

  * As we continue to develop our business, we may also buy or sell all or part of our business. In such transactions, personal information you have shared with us is generally one of the business assets that will be transferred. The transferred personal information will remain subject to the promises made in this privacy policy or subsequent policies to which you have consented. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

  * other people where we have your consent.

We do not share, sell, rent or trade personal information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

### International Data Transfers 

When we share data, it may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country you live in – such as to the United States, where our data hosting provider’s servers are located. These countries may have laws different to what you’re used to. Rest assured, where we disclose personal data to a third party in another country, we put safeguards in place to ensure your personal data remains protected. 

For individuals in the European Economic Area (EEA), this means that your data may be transferred outside of the EEA. Where your personal data is transferred outside the EEA, it will only be transferred to countries that have been identified as providing adequate protection for EEA data (like New Zealand), or to a third party where we have approved transfer mechanisms in place to protect your personal data – i.e., by entering into the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses, or by ensuring the entity is Privacy Shield certified (for transfers to US-based third parties). For further information, please contact us using the details set out in the Contact us section below. 

### Retention 

The length of time we keep your personal data depends on what it is and whether we have an ongoing business need to retain it (for example, to provide you with a service you’ve requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements). 

We’ll retain your personal data for as long as we have a relationship with you and for a period of time afterwards where we have an ongoing business need to retain it, in accordance with our data retention policies and practices. Following that period, we’ll make sure it’s deleted or anonymised. 

### Billing information

Should you sign up for a Crably paid account, register a domain through us, or purchase another premium service, we require your billing information in order to process the transaction.  
We will retain the last 4 digits of your credit card number, credit card type, name, address, and some other billing information, so that you may identify that card used in the future. We do not store your credit card number or CVV2; this information is discarded after your transaction has been processed.  
If your subscription is auto-renewing, a third party Payment Gateway (like Paypal, Stripe, Paymill, etc ) will store your credit card information on their secure payment gateway for as long as necessary to carry out the terms of your subscription.  
All transactions are processed over an industry standard SSL/TLS connection, with a minimum of 128-bit encryption. 

### Information Relating to Children

Individuals under the age of 18 are prohibited from creating or using accounts through Crably.com. 

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Crably may revise, modify or update this policy. We will notify you about significant or material changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your particular Crably account or by placing a prominent notice on our site prior to the change becoming effective. 

### Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

Widgets may also support functions that require that you disclose certain personal information given the user's choice of participation. This information is collected in many different ways such as: forms, surveys, contests, forums, subscribing or unsubscribing to mailings and correcting or updating personal information and are only used for the purpose in which they were collected. Forms which require sensitive information, such as financial information (credit card) to process purchases for products or services, are SSL encrypted to protect your sensitive information. 

### Links to 3rd Party Sites

Our Site includes links to other Websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Crably IVS. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Website you visit. 

### Confidentiality and Security

No data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make efforts to ensure security on our systems. 

  * __We use physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect personal information about you.
  * __Your account information is password-protected.
  * __In certain areas, Crably uses industry-standard SSL-encryption to protect data transmissions (such as when entering credit card details). However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software.

If Crably learns of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using Crably or providing personal data information to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of those sites, products and services. We may post a notice on our applicable web sites if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the applicable web sites. We may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at support@crably.com. 

### Your rights

It’s your personal data and you have certain rights. When it comes to marketing communications, you can ask us not to send you these at any time – just follow the unsubscribe instructions contained in the marketing communication, or send your request to privacy@crably.com.

You also have rights to:

  * Know what personal data we hold about you, and to make sure it’s correct and up to date

  * Request a copy of your personal data, or ask us to restrict processing your personal data or delete it

  * Object to our continued processing of your personal data

You can exercise these rights at any time by sending an email to privacy@crably.com.

If you’re not happy with how we are processing your personal data, please let us know by sending an email to privacy@crably.com. We will review and investigate your complaint, and try to get back to you within a reasonable time frame. You can also complain to your local data protection authority. They will be able to advise you how to submit a complaint.

### You have the right to appeal to the Data Inspectorate

Crably(as data controller) is subject to personal data law (including the EU Personal Data Regulation and National Personal Data Law) provisions on the processing of personal information.

If you experience an infringement of your privacy while using our website or in any other interaction with Crably, you may appeal to the Data Inspectorate.

The Data Inspectorate's contact information is shown below:

Datatilsynet  
Borgergade 28, 5  
1300 København K

Phone number: 33 19 32 00

Email: dt@datatilsynet.dk  

### Contact Information

If you have a privacy concern regarding Crably, or this policy, and if you cannot satisfactorily resolve it through the use of those sites, products or services, you can write to us by email at privacy@crably.com.

Crably is data manager and we ensure that your personal data is processed in accordance with the laws.

We are registered in Denmark under registration number _DK_ 36043865, and our registered office is at _Bellahøjvej 131 st, 2720 Vanløse, Denmark_

Last updated on May 2018.
